# JOSHUA ROGERS

Proven Success in Systems Optimization and Strategic IT Solutions jrogers@rdfindustries.com – https://joshrdfi.github.io

Accomplished network and systems administrator with over 20 years' experience in Information Technology, moving into Data Science with a focus on Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. Feel free to look through my personal GitHub page (linked above) for projects I have completed, and the skills learned from them.

### **QUALIFICATIONS AND SKILLS**

- Self-motivated and results-driven: WGU and Udacity coursework completed early.
- Proven ability in project leadership: Managed teams to complete projects on time and under budget. Managed multiple field technicians across several states, providing fast response times to client issues.
- Skilled in data wrangling, modeling, visualization, and machine learning.
- Delivered software products built using Python and C++.
- Familiarity with modern data analysis, dashboarding and machine learning tools.

- Ability to learn any software very quickly within a Windows or Linux environment.
- Exceptional ability to clearly communicate insights through Tableau, PowerPoint, and Excel.
- Clear understanding of machine learning algorithms: KNN, naive Bayes, SVM, Decision Trees and SGD.
- Strong knowledge of relational databases: SQL, data modeling, query tuning, etc.
- Proficiency in HTML, PHP, and WordPress.
- Takes ownership of my work with dynamic attention to detail.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Lead Technician/Programmer

2/2017 - Current (Per-Contract basis)

Placer Automation

Citrus Heights, CA

- > Automation systems (Vantage/LeGrand, Lutron, Crestron) in high end residential applications, covering system design, install, test, configure and system programming.
- > Interface with clients over complete project cycle to determine needs and implement plan to complete full scope of projects.
- Reading blueprints to trace electrical and communication wiring.
- > Installation of new electrical wiring including tie-in to breaker panels and finish work.
- > Electrical system testing and connection to automation systems.
- Site security covering design, placement, installation, and configuration of IP cameras (ONVIF), network video recorders and integration into existing alarm system.

#### Owner

12/2010 - Current

RDF Industries, Inc.

Sheridan, WY

- > Set up and maintain computers, servers, and networks, including security systems for client companies.
- > Prepare and execute implementation plans for new networks and additions to existing networks.
- Perform general system maintenance, including patch management.
- Write custom shell scripts (Bash, Python) for server management tasks.
- Custom website development with WordPress for several diverse industries.
- > Design and implement Social Media marketing strategies for multiple client companies.
- > Solar power system design and implementation, including battery backup for both off-grid and hybrid systems.

#### **Data Center Level 3 Technician**

8/2016 – 8/2022 Solid Personnel Pleasanton, CA

- ➤ Project lead at multiple SV sites: managed teams to complete projects within budget even during set-backs due to parts/equipment delays.
- Multistory Comba DAS systems (multi-carrier 4G/Emergency/Fire) installation and testing w/ Anritsu equipment.
- > AV system installation from initial cabling to finished floors, Crestron equipment setup and configuration.
- Installing, replacing and or removing media, equipment, hardware and/or components.
- ➤ Identify, pull, terminate, and label ethernet, 16/2 speaker, alarm/secure access wiring and fiber optic cables.
- Installed and configured Cisco/Merkari WAP devices, routers, and switches.
- Production of multi-location network diagrams both in Excel and Visio.
- Configuration and use of Infoblox DDI security solution and Cisco DNA.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# Western Governors University BS Data Management and Data Analysis

Currently enrolled; graduating October 2023

Certifications	<b>Issuing Organization</b>	<b>Completion Date</b>
Data Analyst Nanodegree	Udacity / WGU	05/2023
CIW Data Analyst	CIW Advisory Council	05/2022
Project+	CompTIA	04/2022
A+	CompTIA	07/2020
Secure Infrastructure Specialist	CompTIA	07/2020
IT Operations Specialist	CompTIA	07/2020
Security+	CompTIA	04/2004
Network+	CompTIA	08/2003
National Incident Command Structure: ICS-100 and ICS-200	FEMA	08/2022
Community Emergency Response Team (CERT)	Gilroy CERT	09/2022

#### **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

- Hobby Maker: 3D printing, SBC (Raspberry Pi, Arduino, etc.) electronics experimentation
- General class licensed Amateur Radio Operator
- Neural network and LLM design and development
- IEEE Computer Society member
- Emergency Preparedness and Disaster Response
- Longevity research and supplement formulation